Support Admin Watch on kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
دعم المشرف شاهد على kissasia.cam أو kisskh.org
Stop hitting me.
توقف عن ضربي.
Xiao Yuan Yuan
شياو يوان يوان
Gongzhu
قونغتشو
You're really too frail.
أنت ضعيف جدًا حقًا.
It was just pretend fighting.
لقد كان مجرد تظاهر بالقتال.
How did you still faint?
كيف مازلت أغمى عليك؟
No.
لا.
I shouted so loud I ran out of air.
صرخت بصوت عالي حتى نفد الهواء مني.
Look at you—
انظر اليك—
Living comfortably in the palace,
العيش بشكل مريح في القصر،
with so many people serving you,
مع وجود العديد من الأشخاص الذين يخدمونك،
and you still want to run away.
ومازلت تريد الهروب.
Gongzhu,
قونغتشو،
I'm just a commoner.
أنا مجرد شخص عادي.
I can't stand all this palace luxury.
لا أستطيع أن أتحمل كل هذا الفخامة القصرية.
Please, let me go.
من فضلك دعني أذهب.
Absurd.
سخيف.
Without my protection,
بدون حمايتي،
you'd be like a lamb to the slaughter.
سوف تكون مثل الحمل إلى الذبح.
If I hadn't saved you,
لو لم أنقذك،
you'd be a Drunken Flowers patron by now.
لقد أصبحت الآن أحد رعاة Drunken Flowers.
Xiao Yuan Yuan,
شياو يوان يوان,
don't worry.
لا تقلق.
Just stay obediently in the palace,
فقط ابق مطيعا في القصر،
and I promise
وأنا أعدك
you'll have wealth and honor.
سيكون لديك الثروة والشرف.
Chengzhu
تشنغتشو
Du Momo is here.
أنت مومو هنا.
Your servant greets Chengzhu.
خادمك يحيي تشنغتشو.
Du Momo
يو مومو
You watched Feng'er grow up.
لقد شاهدت فينغ'ر يكبر.
As long as you're by her side,
طالما كنت بجانبها
I can rest easy.
أستطيع أن أرتاح بسهولة.
She recently took in a scholar.
لقد أخذت مؤخرا طالبا في الجامعة.
He's quite talented.
إنه موهوب جدًا.
I've made him Feng'er's study companion.
لقد جعلته رفيق دراسة فينج إير.
But he's from Yue.
ولكنه من يوي.
He knows nothing of our palace etiquette
لا يعرف شيئا عن آداب قصرنا
or our rules.
أو قواعدنا.
Take this chance
اغتنم هذه الفرصة
to teach him well.
لتعليمه جيدا.
Yes.
نعم.
I will do my best to ease your worries.
سأبذل قصارى جهدي لتخفيف مخاوفك.
By the way,
بالمناسبة،
the other scholars in her palace
العلماء الآخرين في قصرها
should be properly disciplined too.
ينبغي أن يكون منضبطًا بشكل صحيح أيضًا.
It's a mess in there.
إنها فوضى هناك.
It's upsetting to see.
من المحزن أن نرى ذلك.
Yes.
نعم.
I won't let you down.
لن أخذلك .
Xie Yuan, oh Xie Yuan,
شي يوان، أوه شي يوان،
you're so clueless.
أنت جاهل تماما.
That tyrant mother and daughter
تلك الأم الطاغية وابنتها
would never punish their own.
لن يعاقبوا أنفسهم أبدًا.
Now you're her study companion.
أنت الآن رفيق دراستها.
Escaping is nearly impossible.
الهروب يكاد يكون مستحيلا.
No way.
مستحيل.
I have to leave tonight.
يجب علي أن أغادر الليلة.
Wait, no.
انتظر، لا.
I haven't found my Records of Origins yet.
لم أعثر على سجلاتي الأصلية بعد.
Why take the clothes she gave me?
لماذا تأخذ الملابس التي أعطتني إياها؟
Xiao Yuan Yuan,
شياو يوان يوان,
are you leaving?
هل انت مغادر؟
Aren't you the study companion now?
أليس أنت رفيق الدراسة الآن؟
I took from my bundle
أخذت من حزمتي
the clothes you gave me.
الملابس التي أعطيتني إياها.
Pick one that suits you.
اختار ما يناسبك.
Xiao Yuan Yuan,
شياو يوان يوان,
I didn't expect you to care so much.
لم أتوقع أنك تهتم بهذا القدر.
It's my fault for neglecting you.
إنه خطئي أني أهملك.
I didn't prepare proper clothes for you.
لم اقم بإعداد الملابس المناسبة لك.
Don't worry.
لا تقلق.
As long as you stay in the palace,
ما دمت في القصر،
I promise
أعدك
to give you the best of everything.
لنقدم لكم الأفضل من كل شيء.
That's really not necessary.
هذا ليس ضروريا حقا.
Xiao Yuan Yuan,
شياو يوان يوان,
then
ثم
rest early.
الراحة مبكرا.
Escaped trouble again.
نجا من المتاعب مرة أخرى.
But how much longer can I hide?
ولكن إلى متى يمكنني أن أختبئ؟
Once I find the Records of Origins,
بمجرد أن أجد سجلات الأصول،
I must find a way to escape.
يجب أن أجد طريقة للهروب.
For now, I have to compromise.
في الوقت الحالي، لا بد لي من التوصل إلى حل وسط.
Gongzhu
قونغتشو
It's time to get up.
حان وقت الاستيقاظ.
Xie Gongzi is here!
شيه قونغزي هنا!
What?
ماذا؟
Xie Gongzi is here.
Xie Gongzi هنا.
Hurry, hurry!
اسرع اسرع!
Dress me up, quickly!
ألبسني بسرعة!
Gongzhu
قونغتشو
I lied to you.
لقد كذبت عليك.
You brat!
يا لك من شقي!
Greetings, Gongzhu.
تحياتي، قونغزو.
Du Momo
يو مومو
Why are you here?
لماذا انت هنا؟
I just told Xiao Tao
لقد أخبرت شياو تاو للتو
I'd visit you when I have time.
سأزورك عندما يكون لدي الوقت.
Yes, Du Momo,
نعم انت مومو
Gongzhu often says she wants to visit you.
تقول Gongzhu في كثير من الأحيان أنها تريد زيارتك.
Gongzhu's words humble me.
كلمات جونجزو أذلتني.
Chengzhu sent me.
لقد أرسلها لي تشنغتشو.
I heard Gongzhu recruited
سمعت أن جونجتشو قام بالتجنيد
a scholar from Yue.
عالم من يوي.
Chengzhu ordered me
أمرني Chengzhu
to teach him rules and etiquette.
لتعليمه القواعد والآداب.
So it's for Xiao Yuan Yuan.
لذا فهو من أجل شياو يوان يوان.
That's fine.
هذا جيّد.
Du Momo is strict.
أنت مومو صارم.
I won't have to worry anymore.
لن أحتاج للقلق بعد الآن.
Alright, Du Momo.
حسنًا، دو مومو.
I'll have Xiao Tao
سوف أحصل على شياو تاو
bring Xie Yuan to the main hall.
أحضر شي يوان إلى القاعة الرئيسية.
Wait.
انتظر.
There's more.
هناك المزيد.
Gongzhu, gather everyone
جونجتشو، اجمع الجميع
in your residence.
في محل إقامتك.
Let me see them.
دعني أراهم.
See if they serve you well.
انظر إذا كانوا يخدمونك بشكل جيد.
Alright.
على ما يرام.
Du Momo
يو مومو
We'll go together later.
سنذهب معًا لاحقًا.
Yes.
نعم.
This—
هذا-
the study companion's clothes
ملابس رفيق الدراسة
are quite refined.
هي راقية جدًا.
Gongzi
جونجزي
You've gone from scholar to study companion.
لقد انتقلت من طالب إلى رفيق دراسة.
You're the first ever.
أنت الأول على الإطلاق.
I don't need this.
لا أحتاج لهذا.
Take it away.
خذها بعيدا.
But palace rules say
لكن قواعد القصر تقول
men must wear rouge when going out.
يجب على الرجال ارتداء اللون الأحمر عند الخروج.
Is there a rule
هل هناك قاعدة
that you must obey your master?
أنك يجب أن تطيع سيدك؟
I don't need it. Take it away.
لا أحتاجه. خذه بعيدًا.
Yes.
نعم.
Young Master Xie, come with me quickly.
السيد الشاب شيه، تعال معي بسرعة.
Gongzhu asked you to go learn etiquette.
طلب منك Gongzhu أن تتعلم آداب السلوك.
Even the study companion must learn etiquette?
حتى رفيق الدراسة يجب أن يتعلم الآداب؟
You'll know once you go.
سوف تعرف بمجرد ذهابك.
Gongzhu, Young Master Xie is here.
Gongzhu، السيد الشاب Xie هنا.
You are
أنت
Xie Yuan.
شيه يوان.
You see Gongzhu,
ترى Gongzhu،
why don't you bow?
لماذا لا تنحني؟
Why should I bow?
لماذا يجب أن انحني؟
Du Momo.
انت مومو.
Um...
واحد...
I'm having a spat with him.
أنا في خلاف معه.
Isn't that right, Xie Yuan?
أليس هذا صحيحًا، شي يوان؟
Bow.
قَوس.
Du Momo.
انت مومو.
Young Master Xie.
السيد الشاب شيه.
Let me warn you first.
دعني أحذرك أولاً.
I'm here by the City Lord's order.
أنا هنا بأمر من سيد المدينة.
I'm here to teach you what etiquette is.
أنا هنا لأعلمك ما هي الآداب.
And what rules are.
وما هي القواعد؟
Do you know, in this palace,
هل تعلم أنه في هذا القصر
what you most need to learn?
ما هو الشيء الذي تحتاج إلى تعلمه أكثر؟
Do you all know?
هل تعلمون جميعا؟
No.
لا.
In this palace,
في هذا القصر،
the most important thing to learn
أهم شيء يجب تعلمه
is Male Virtue.
هي الفضيلة الذكورية.
You truly know nothing
أنت لا تعرف شيئا حقا
about Male Virtue.
حول الفضيلة الذكورية.
Men should value gentleness and harmony.
ينبغي على الرجال أن يقدروا اللطف والانسجام.
Step down.
انزل.
Standing so straight—
الوقوف بشكل مستقيم
are you trying to outshine Gongzhu?
هل تحاول التفوق على Gongzhu؟
You—
أنت-
Step down, now.
انزل الآن.
Down.
تحت.
Du Momo.
انت مومو.
Um...
واحد...
He didn't mean that.
لم يقصد ذلك.
Serving Gongzhu,
خدمة قونغتشو،
your face has no makeup at all.
وجهك ليس به أي مكياج على الإطلاق.
You're really being careless.
أنت مهمل حقا.
Someone, come.
أحد ما، تعال.
I'll do your makeup myself.
سأقوم بوضع مكياجك بنفسي.
You—
أنت-
How dare you—
كيف تجرؤ؟
How dare you, how dare—
كيف تجرؤ، كيف تجرؤ-
How dare you!
كيف تجرؤ!
That's tall enough.
هذا طويل بما فيه الكفاية.
Now that's more like it.
الآن أصبح الأمر أشبه بذلك.
I'm not that talented,
أنا لست موهوبًا إلى هذه الدرجة،
but those I've taught Male Virtue
لكن هؤلاء الذين علمتهم الفضيلة الذكورية
have become proper gentlemen.
لقد أصبحوا سادة حقيقيين.
Countless, in fact.
لا تعد ولا تحصى، في الواقع.
This time, I've come
هذه المرة، لقد جئت
to design a special course for you.
لتصميم دورة خاصة لك.
This is the palace's finest compilation.
هذه هي أفضل مجموعة في القصر.
You must memorize it well.
يجب عليك حفظه جيدا.
Also, do you see
هل ترى أيضا
those things?
تلك الأشياء؟
Those over there?
أولئك هناك؟
They're materials for your needlework.
إنها مواد لتطريزك.
Your embroidery must also improve.
يجب عليك أيضًا تحسين التطريز الخاص بك.
The rest,
البقية،
I'll teach him slowly.
سأعلمه ببطء.
But
لكن
more importantly,
والأهم من ذلك،
next time you see Gongzhu,
في المرة القادمة عندما ترى Gongzhu،
if your face lacks makeup again,
إذا كان وجهك يفتقر إلى المكياج مرة أخرى،
I'll report to the City Lord.
سأبلغ إلى سيد المدينة.
That won't be a simple punishment.
لن يكون هذا عقابًا بسيطًا.
Absurd!
سخيف!
Come back here!
عد إلى هنا!
Xie Yuan.
شيه يوان.
Don't worry, Du Momo.
لا تقلق، دو مومو.
I'll make sure to supervise him well.
سأتأكد من الإشراف عليه جيدًا.
Let's have some tea first.
دعونا نشرب بعض الشاي أولا.
Just agree to it.
فقط وافق على ذلك.
Du Momo is very skilled at training people.
يتمتع دو مومو بمهارة كبيرة في تدريب الأشخاص.
Though a scholar may die, never be humiliated,
وإن مات العالم فلا يذل أبدا،
but under another's roof,
ولكن تحت سقف آخر،
one must bow their head.
يجب على الإنسان أن يحني رأسه.
I
أنا
will take good care of Gongzhu.
سوف أعتني بـ Gongzhu جيدًا.
That's more like it.
هذا هو أكثر مثل ذلك.
Bring it here.
احضره هنا.
Take it.
خذها.
Clean the entire Gongzhu's residence
تنظيف مسكن جونجزو بالكامل
from top to bottom.
من الأعلى إلى الأسفل.
That's all.
هذا كل شئ.
Understood?
مفهوم؟
Du Momo.
انت مومو.
Let's go have tea first.
دعنا نذهب لشرب الشاي أولاً.
Remember that.
تذكر ذلك.
Go, go, go.
إذهب! إذهب! إذهب.
Let's go have tea, let's go.
دعنا نذهب لشرب الشاي، دعنا نذهب.
Do a good job.
قم بعمل جيد.
Go.
يذهب.
What tea does Gongzhu drink?
ما هو الشاي الذي يشربه جونجزو؟
Bi Luo Chun.
بي لوه تشون.
Bi Luo Chun is great.
بي لو تشون رائع.